So, when we first started counting herring, so it was 2012, and, you know, the rules
were a little looser and, you know, you just had to ask permission, and you could bring
some people to observe and see what you're doing.
So I loaded the car with kids - just my son and a couple of friends - and, you know, I
baited them with fishing rods because, you know, they wouldn't really want to go see
fish, but they'd want to go fishing.
So I had them there and so I did my count and then I- we talked about dams, and how they
are a rude interrupter with, you know, habitats and that type of thing, and we just had a great
discussion about dams and, you know, this one was replaced with a fish ladder which
allowed the herring to migrate - and the eels, and whatever snuck in there as well.
So, we had a great time, and the next day I get a phone call from the boy's mother and
she said, "You wouldn't believe it.
"The boys," - well, all the sixth graders - "had their MCAS and the open response question
"was: 'Name and describe a man-made structure that interrupts,'" - or, they probably didn't
say "interrupt", but that, you know - "'disturbs the natural ecology.'"
"And, you gave them the answer, Karen!"
(laughing)