So, when we first started counting herring, so 2012, the rules were a little looser, and
you just had to ask permission, and you could bring some people to observe and see what
you're doing.
So, I loaded the car with kids, just my son and a couple of friends, and I baited them
with fishing rods, because they wouldn't really want to go see fish, but they'd want to go
fishing.
So, I had them there, and so I did my count, and then we talked about dams and how they
are a rude interrupter with habitats and that type of thing, and we just had a great
discussion about dams, and this one was replaced with a fish ladder, which allowed the herring
to migrate, and the eels and whatever snuck in there as well.
So, we had a great time, and the next day, I get a phone call from the boy's mother,
and she said, "You wouldn't believe it."
The boys, well, all the sixth graders had their MCAS, and the open response question
was, "Name and describe a man-made structure that," or they probably didn't say interrupter,
"but that disturbs the natural ecology," and you gave them the answer, Karen.
(laughs)